planetshoes.com 2016-03-29

# PLANET SHOES - Privacy Policy - Help Center

Thank you for visiting the PlanetShoes.com website (“Site”). We take your privacy seriously, and we want you to know how we collect, use, share, and protect your information. 

This Privacy Policy tells you: 

  * What information we collect
  * How we use that information
  * How we may share that information
  * How we protect your information
  * Your choices regarding your personal information

Please note that by visiting the Site directly or through another site, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

##### Information Collection

Information You Give Us  
We receive and may store any information you enter on the Site. For example, we collect information from you when you place an order, create an account, call us with a question, write a review, or use any of our services. 

The information we collect from you includes, but is not limited to, things like: 

  * Your name
  * Your e-mail address
  * Your phone number
  * Your credit card number and other payment information

The information we collect from you may also include information you give us about other people, such as the name and address of a gift recipient. 

Automatic Information  
Like many other websites, we also collect information through automated means. Although our site servers collect information about a user’s internet protocol address, our server is not able to automatically associate that information with a particular user. For example, we may collect non-identifying information associated with that address, such as the time and date of a visit, the originating domain name, the browser type, and the particular pages or products viewed on the site. 

PlanetShoes.com may utilize a “cookie.” A “cookie” is a small text file that a website can place on your computer’s hard drive in order to collect information about your activities on the website. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you have the option to change your browser to decline them. We use cookies on certain pages of our websites, but these cookies are not used to identify anonymous site visitors. Our cookies enable you to proceed smoothly through our sites and enable us to know whether you’ve visited our sites before to eliminate some steps that are directed to new visitors. Similarly, a cookie may be placed by our third-party advertising companies. These companies may use aggregated statistics about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide you with advertisements about goods and services that you may be interested in. The information they collect does not include your personal information. 

Image tags work in conjunction with cookies. An image tag, also referred to as a clear GIF or web beacon, is a small image file that may be located on select pages on our websites. 

The third-party advertising companies may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of ads. Any such information is anonymous. They may use this anonymous information about your visits to this and other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of potential interest to you. No personal information about you is collected during this process. The information is anonymous and does not link online actions to an identifiable person. If you would like more information and want to explore the option of not having this information collected by third-party advertisers click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

At this time, PlanetShoes.com has contracted with Google to collect information about how website users navigate our websites. This information will be used only to generate anonymous visitor profiles, which do not contain personally identifiable information. The anonymous profiles are used to provide website users content specifically tailored to them. To opt out of Google’s collection of information about how you navigate our websites, please go to <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>. 

There are unrelated, third party web sites, such as third party online retailers, advertisers, or unrelated sites that we may link to, or that link to our website, these third parties may collect personal information directly from you. The information policies and practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. We do not control the privacy policies of third parties even if we provide hyperlinks or other access to their web sites. We are not responsible or liable for their independent policies and practices. Please review their privacy policies and practices. It is your responsibility to review them and decide if you are satisfied with their protections. 

##### Information Use

We use the information we collect for things, including but not limited to, the following: 

  * Fulfilling orders and requests for products or information
  * Processing returns
  * Tracking and confirming online orders
  * Marketing and advertising products and services
  * Conducting research and analysis
  * Establishing and managing your accounts with us
  * Communicating things like special events, sweepstakes, promotions and surveys
  * Identifying you on our websites and tailoring advertisements and offers to you (both on our websites and on other websites) based upon your visits to PlanetShoes.com and other websites
  * Operating, evaluating and improving our business

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, and as we may otherwise deem appropriate. 

##### Information Sharing

PlanetShoes.com does not sell, rent or trade your personal information with/to third parties. 

We may share your information with third parties to perform services on our behalf such as: 

  * Fulfilling orders
  * Delivering packages
  * Sending PlanetShoes.com marketing communications
  * Conducting research and analysis
  * Providing chat functions

Sometimes we may be required to share personal information in response to a regulation, court order or subpoena. We may also share information when we believe it's necessary or appropriate to comply with any rules, regulations, and laws. We also may share information in response to a government or regulatory agency request or when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate: (a) to protect the rights, property or safety of PlanetShoes.com, our customers, or others; (b) and/or to prevent harm or loss; (c) and/or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity. 

We may also share personal information in the event of a corporate sale, merger, acquisition, change in control, dissolution, or similar event that involves or affects the Site. 

##### Information Security

We take commercially reasonable steps to protect the information we collect online. However, as effective as these measures are, no security system is impenetrable. We do not provide an absolute guarantee of the security of our information databases, nor do we guarantee that the information you may choose to supply will not be intercepted while you transmit it from your computer, over the internet, or along other third party networks, and to our systems. However, with respect to security: when we request the transfer of certain types of sensitive information, we redirect visitors to a secure server using, for example, Secure Sockets Layer security. 

##### Your Choices

Upon your request, we will (a) correct any information we have about you; (b) stop sending e-mails to your e-mail address; and/or (c) disable your account to prevent any future purchases through that account. Please make these requests by contacting our Customer Service department by one of the following methods: 

**Call:**  
(888) 818-7463 

Customer Service Representatives are available to assist you Monday through Friday,  
10:00 am – 8:00 pm EST.

**E-mail:**  

**Write:**  
PlanetShoes.com  
Attn: Customer Service Department  
57 Chapel Street  
Suite 200  
Newton, MA 02458

In the event we amend this Privacy Policy, posting the amended version will serve as notice to you of that change and the amended Privacy Policy will note its effective date. 

Effective May 2, 2012
